Jan Klug

Polymath Product Manager of 5 years, before that: UX, programming and startup financing. I've handled a broad range of products in a variety of roles; equally happy during customer visits, code reviews and C-suite meetings. Hungry for hard Product, Technical and Strategic problems to solve with good people. 3rd culture kid, working on my 7th language; I like to listen to people more than I talk.

Skills, Tooling & Technologies

Skills: Agile Product Management, Behaviour-Driven Development (Gherkin), Data-Driven Decision Making, Financial Modelling, Information Architecture, Offshoring, Organizational Design, Project Management, Requirements Gathering, Roadmap Prioritization and Execution, Software Engineering, Stakeholder Management, Strategic Planning, Technical Specification, UX Research, Wireframing

Tooling: Apple Testflight, Autodesk Sketchbook, Azure DevOPs (VSTS), Google Analytics, Google Cloud Platform (Auth, Firebase, Firestore, Hosting), Google Play Console, InVision, Jira, Lucidchart, Microsoft Office Suite, Power BI, SQL, Trello, Zendesk

Technologies: AngularJS, C#, CSS, HTML, Ionic, Java, .Net Core, Node.js, Python, Unity, Vue.js

Experience

Portfolio Product Manager - Ticketer | November 2017-Present | Transport Apps, Hardware and SaaS

Managing portfolio of products powering 80% of UK regional bus travel and moving 2bn people per year, including: real-time tracking and operational SaaS, on-bus ticketing and payments devices, commercial APIs, passenger-facing mobile apps and webapps.

- **Pitched leadership** on product cases based on analysis of new strategic opportunities, e.g. systems enabling on-demand bus services and APIs powering real-time travel apps
- **Product lead from inception to launch** of new products like UK's first multi-operator passenger ticketing marketplace and navigation **app**. Managed two **offshore teams** throughout build process. **Analyzed** UX feedback/analytics, adjusting roadmap to **prioritize** ticketing features enabling earlier shipping.
- Ran customer requirement gathering sessions, reviewed sales/support feedback to establish highest ROI
 enhancements to existing products, enabling us to sign our 2 largest customers, scaling revenue by 50%
- Collaborated with design, engineering and QA to prototype and specify features, anticipating UX and technical challenges to reduce rework by average of 1 week
- Planned sprints with Infrastructure, SaaS, Mobile and QA team leads, managing resourcing and timelines, reporting to senior leadership
- Chaired sprint kickoffs and managed agile delivery throughout execution and testing, created documentation/training for 20-strong support and sales team on new product and feature deployments
- Managed integration projects with **Apple** (enabling Apple Pay Express Transit across most UK buses), **Google** (cannot disclose pending launch), and **Sapphire** (allowing Infor EAM to query and update fleet status)
- Advised Department for Transport on the Bus Open Data Digital Service, improving technical architecture and regulation, reducing unnecessary costs and security threats to bus operators. Designed COVID-19 analytics dashboard for DfT to monitor regional bus travel fluctations
- Championed and implemented better ways of working (e.g. devolving sprint planning from CTO to team leads) and cleared management bottlenecks by empowering design and engineering to make decisions (Shape-Up)
- Established communications between engineering, support, and sales accelerating bug inquiries by 80%
- Trained 3 junior product analysts, growing product team capabilities to manage more in parallel

Product Manager - Go4Venture | July 2015 - November 2017 | Fintech SaaS

Managed spin-out of startup financing marketplace and investment research platform from UK's leading tech-sector investment bank, Silverpeak.

• Used modern tooling and **in-house SQL database** to establish tech-enabled investment banking practice, enabling team to efficiently **manage 2x as many financing projects**

- Assumed ownership of legacy product, establishing bug tracking, analytics and oversaw backend migration
- Translated learnings from investment banking into automated matchmaking and fundraising web platform for startups and investors
- Implemented user-centred design process and backlog prioritisation methodologies
- Scoped MVP and personally coded prototype in AngularJS for user testing of major platform rebuild

Corporate Finance Analyst - Silverpeak Technology Investment Banking | July 2012 - July 2015 | Startup M&A

Advised startup and scale-up companies from pre-raise through funding completion, and on M&A.

- Facilitated sale of real-time unified threat detection provider, AnubisNetworks, to BitSight
- Facilitated sale of provider of optical sensors for critical assets, FiberSensing, to Spectris
- Provided startup portfolio analysis consultancy and organised pitch days for Portugal Ventures
- Selected M&A targets and benchmarked industry for an undisclosed FTSE-100 software provider
- Researched, edited and published monthly tech sector fundraising coverage read by 5,000 subscribers
- Self-taught programming to automate job tasks, resigned to study MSc Computer Science at UCL

Corporate Finance Analyst Long Term Intern - Rothschild | February 2012 - July 2012 | Investment Banking (For details and prior experience see <u>LinkedIn</u>)

Projects

(For full portfolio see jan-made.com)

Cities Unlocked - Microsoft & University College London | June 2016 - September 2016

Led design and developed on Cities Unlocked mobility tool providing navigation, orientation and exploration features for the visually impaired.

- As scrum master and client liaison with Microsoft UK head of project UX, shipped cross-platform C# Unity app and .NET API
- Gathered requirements from target users, designing purpose-built interface and out-of-box experience to be optimally learnable for visually impaired users
- Personally coded a reusable interface library, VR tutorial, and recommendation feature
- Prototype learnings productionized as Microsoft Soundscape

LongVA - European Space Agency & University College London | October 2015 - January 2016

Architected system for performing longitudinal voice analysis on users to monitor psychological state (for eventual use in deep space missions)

- Coordinated team building a server backend to accept hi-fi audio uploads from mobile client
- Designed UX for mobile app for optimal recording quality balanced with minimising effort for user.
- Personally coded cross-platform mobile app in Ionic + AngularJS using native hardware APIs for high fidelity recording

Education

MSc Computer Science 1st Class Honours with Distinction - University College London | 2016 BA Philosophy Politics & Economics Upper 2nd Class Honours - Durham University | 2010

Personal

Languages: Fluent English, Advanced German & Mandarin, Intermediate French & Cantonese, Basic Japanese & Italian.

Nationalities: German Citizenship, Hong Kong Citizenship, China Permanent Work and Residency Permit, UK Residency.

Interests: Carpentry, Cinema, Cooking, Pen & Paper Role Playing Games, Philosophy, Powerlifting.